<teiCorpus><TEI><text><body><biblScope>92</biblScope>
<p>enormity of the evils of Negro slavery, with a view to excite the attention of the public, and, through them, of Parliament to the subject. On the wisdom and justice of Parliament we place an implicit reliance. Let the evils be only examined and ascertained, and we cannot doubt that appropriate remedies will be discovered and applied. Neither can we doubt that, in applying them, a due regard will be paid to whatever claims <interp key="reason" n="citation" cert="high" ref="http://abolition.e2bn.org/slavery_110.html"></interp> may have on the liberality of the nation.</p><p>The present publication, it seems right to mention, has originated with an association at <placeName key="Liverpool, United Kingdom" ref="http://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Liverpool&params=53_4_00_N_3_00_00_W_type:city_region:GB"></placeName>, formed for the express purpose of employing all and prudent means for mitigating and finally abolishing the state of slavery throughout the British dominions. Similar associations are already formed in the metropolis and in other parts of the United Kingdom. But it became <placeName key="Liverpool, United Kingdom" ref="http://tools.wmflabs.org/geohack/geohack.php?pagename=Liverpool&params=53_4_00_N_3_00_00_W_type:city_region:GB"></placeName>, long the deepest in the guilt of the Slave-trade, to come forward the first to protest against the perpetuation of the original injustice of that criminal traffic, in the persons of the descendants of its earlier victims. Such associations, we trust, will be multiplied in every corner of the realm, and will never intermit their united and strenuous efforts, until by exposition, petition, remonstrance, and every legal method of intervention, they wipe out this foul stain from the character of their country, and deliver themselves from all participation in a system which, as has now been demonstrated, in-volves the violation of every acknowledged principle of the religion of Christ.</p><p>THE END</p>
</body></text></TEI></teiCorpus>